Seena Rowhani

Software Developer

Ottawa, Ontario CA

🗘 srowhani in Seena Rowhani 🕇 seena.rowhani

Passionate developer with a demonstrated history in full-stack development. Years of experience developing with Javascript/CSS, using a variety of popular frameworks (Ember, React, Aurelia, Vue, ...), writing enterprise back-end software, developing software solutions for cloud (AWS, GCS), as well as automated testing/build configurations.

LANGUAGES

English Farsi native speaker fluent

SKILLS

Web Development

master

html5 | css3 | javascript | ember.js | react | vue.js | meteor | aurelia

Software Design

advanced

java | c language | c++ | python | golang | android | node.js

Automation, Building, and Testing

advanced

mocha | chai | qunit | gulp | jasmine

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer at Solace May 2017 - September 2017

Worked on the Solace Cloud team, developing a messaging solution offered as service.

- Deploying software as a service on popular cloud services
- Scalable back end architecture experience using Spring
- Designing SPA's using Aurelia
- Build tool configuration using Ansible
- Unit testing enterprise code

Software Developer at Ciena September 2015 - April 2017

http://ciena.com

Worked with amazing talent on the front and back end of products BluePlanet, IceBreaker, and Frost UX style guide.

- Used Ember.js to rapidly create and prototype web apps
- Automated builds, TeamCity and Travis, and ember-deploy to improve workflow
- Command line tools to assist PV contribute to testing ecosystem
- Created Ember addons to be used as tools for other developers as a standard
- Programming experience with Javascript ES6 (using Babel), and node module exports
- Back end using Java's Jersey library, and Google's GSON to parse requests.
- Canvas and d3 SVG visualizations to display complex systems

Software Designer at Nokia (formerly Alcatel-Lucent) May 2015 - September 2015

https://www.alcatel-lucent.com/

Developed along side of extremely talented designers and testers, refining and designing popular applications that would be used both internally and externally.

- Yeoman application scaffolding
- Developed features for Web Applications using popular industry tools

- Experience with popular build, automation, and development interfaces
- Manipulation of both Javascript and Java code base, for front and back-end development
- Created and maintained build tools used by other developers

Web Application Developer at TekWorthy November 2014 - February 2015

http://www.tekworthy.com/

Developed a wide array of web applications for clients to meet their needs, in a given time frame.

- MeteorJS
- Socket Client-Server Development
- MongoDB No SQL database

Teaching Assistant at Carleton University September 2014 - June 2016

http://carleton.ca

Taught many popular programming courses to mainly first year students, aiding them in the process of learning.

- Facilitate weekly office hours, in order to ensure that students are fully understanding the course material, and to provide extra attention to those that need it.
- Conduct tutorial sessions, where students are able to collaboratively complete practice assignments and express their concerns or troubles and work towards a resolution
- Revise and evaluate the students' tests and assignments so that they can benefit from constructive feedback, and ultimately improve their academic performance.
- Collaborated with colleagues and professors to ensure equality between students of different learning stages, such that everyone can be accommodated.

Web Developer at CafeX (formerly Vayyoo) May 2013 - August 2013

- http://vayyoo.com/www/main/
- Developed a 'Getting Started' application using Javascript, CSS, as well as various JS templating libraries, to introduce new clients to the websites available interfaces.
- Debugged iOS, Android, and Web Applications, and created bug reports and appropriate 'push' or feature requests to accommodate the clients' needs.
- Tested Java backend server for time complexity, as well as security and vulnerability. Essentially making sure that the REST API that they were using was working as intended.
- Gained insight into working well with others, time management, and collaboration.

PROJECTS

sl-auto-fix

https://github.com/srowhani/sass-lint-auto-fix

Automatically resolve s(a|c)ss linting issues

Issues are resolved by parsing the s(a|c)ss as an ast, traversing through it, and performing modifications

trendify-app

https://devpost.com/software/trendify-bdsve7

Submission for CUHacking 2018

A web/iOS based game which uses open source google trend module powered by STDLIB to allow users to compete.

proccoli-pm

http://github.com/proccoli/proccoli-pm

Process Manager written in python.

Uses linux's proc virtual fs to persist information and metrics about the system, and uses urwid console interface to render it.

democracy

http://github.com/srowhani/democracy

Visualize voting based on the contents and frequency of tweet hashtags via Twitters Stream API.

Built using: express, socket.io, d3, Ember.js

EDUCATION

Bachelor Computer Science: Honours in Software Engineering at Carleton University

2013 - 2018

Grade: 10.5